And welcome back everybody.
다시 오신 걸 환영해요
Welcome to week two day three.
2주 차에 오신 걸 환영해요 3일째예요
It's a continuation of our enjoyment of radio, our celebration of everything that is radio and user
라디오에 대한 즐거움의 연속이죠 라디오와 사용자 인터페이스에 관한 모든 것을 축하하는
interfaces.
거예요
Uh, what you can already do in addition to using open AI, anthropic and Gemini, you can now also
오픈 인공지능과 인류학 제미니 개발 외에도 여러분의 솔루션에 맞는
build UIs for your solutions.
UI를 구축할 수 있죠
And you should feel pretty good about that.
그러니 기분 좋으시겠어요
Uh, by the end of today, you'll be able to do more.
오늘 저녁쯤엔 더 많은 걸 할 수 있을 거예요
You'll be able to build chat UIs, a specific type of UI which is very common.
채팅 UI를 만들 수 있어요 아주 흔한 특정 유형의 UI죠
You'll be able to provide the history of conversation in a prompt, and you will build your very first
신속하게 대화 이력을 제공할 수 있고 첫 고객 지원 비서를 만들 수 있습니다
customer support assistant, an AI assistant, also known as a chat bot.
채팅 봇이라고도 하는 인공지능 비서요
A very common I use case.
아주 흔한 케이스죠
You will have mastered it today.
오늘 통달할 거예요
So again, very common.
아주 흔한 일이죠
J'en ai use case.
인공지능은 케이스로 사용해요
I think we're all very familiar with them.
다들 잘 아실 거예요
Llms based on chat bots.
채팅봇을 기반으로 한 LM이에요
Super effective at conversation.
대화에 아주 효과적이죠
It's hard to remember that only a few years ago, if you experienced one of these chatbot style interfaces
기억하기 힘들지만 불과 몇 년 전만 해도 챗봇 스타일 인터페이스를 웹사이트에서
on a website, you would be in the world of responding one, two, three, or four to different things,
경험했다면 다른 것에 하나, 둘, 셋, 넷 응답하는 세상에 있었을
or use a keyword like booking or something like that.
거예요 예약 같은 키워드를 사용하거나요
How far we have come.
우리가 얼마나 멀리 왔는지도요
You can now have an informed conversation with customer service chatbots on websites, and you often
고객 서비스 챗봇과 웹사이트에서 정보를 주고받을 수 있어요 자주 그러죠
And, you know, frankly, there have been times when I've got more value from a conversation with a
솔직히 말해서 인간과의 대화보다 챗봇과의 대화가
chatbot than I have from a human being, which is a sorry, sad sense of the times.
더 가치 있었던 때도 있었어요 시대상으로는 안타깝고 슬픈 일이죠
Um, but obviously we can't do things like asking it how many times the letter A appears in that sentence.
하지만 알파벳 A가 문장에 몇 번 나오는지 물어볼 수는 없어요
Uh, but anyways, uh, the, uh, the chatbot use case.
어쨌든 챗봇 사용 사례 말인데요
Very familiar, very important indeed.
아주 친숙하고 중요하죠
And something where llms excel.
llms가 탁월한 것 말이에요
You can imagine some of the things that we're familiar with, the friendly personas that we can give
우리에게 익숙한 것들을 상상해 보세요 챗봇에 붙여주는
chatbots, or indeed any persona we can have the ability to maintain context between messages this staggering
친근한 가명이나 메시지 사이의 컨텍스트를 유지할 수 있는 모든 가명을요 대화를 나누고
way that you can hold a conversation and refer to things that you said earlier.
아까 말한 걸 참조할 수 있는 놀라운 방법이죠
And we all know now that that is some, some, some trickery going on there.
그게 속임수라는 건 다들 알잖아요
It's an illusion that you're really having this persistent conversation.
정말 끈질기게 대화하고 있다는 건 환상이에요
What's happening is at each step.
각 단계마다 달라요
The entire conversation history is being provided to the LLM in order to get back the next response.
모든 대화 기록은 LLM에 제공됩니다 다음 응답을 얻기 위해서죠
Um, and then also these assistants can have subject matter expertise, which they use to answer questions
또한 이 비서들은 주제와 관련된 전문 지식을 갖추고 지식이 풍부한 답변을
in a knowledgeable way.
할 수 있죠
So, uh, very important aspect of interacting with assistants is the correct use of prompts.
비서와의 상호 작용에서 가장 중요한 건 프롬프트 사용의 정확성이에요
We're very familiar now with the system prompt that we can use to set the tone of the conversation.
대화의 분위기를 결정하는 시스템 프롬프트가 이젠 아주 익숙하죠
You can establish ground rules.
기본 규칙을 정할 수 있어요
There is a common prompt technique of saying if you don't know the answer, just say so.
답을 모르면 모른다고 말하는 데 흔히 쓰이는 기법이 있어요
To try and encourage llms to be truthful and not to hallucinate.
환각을 보지 않고 진실하도록 장려하는 거죠
Uh, context is how you can use, uh, the add additional information into the conversation to give
컨텍스트는 대화에 추가 정보를 추가하는 방법을 말합니다 대화 내용에 대해 더 많은
the LLM more context on what's being discussed.
컨텍스트를 제공하기 위해서죠
And then multi shots prompting is when you add information to the prompt to give multiple examples of
Multi숏 프롬프팅은 프롬프트에 정보를 추가하는 것을 뜻합니다 상호 작용
interactions as a way to, uh, craft, to sort of hone the character of the LLM by giving it examples
예제를 여러 개 제공하는 거죠 작업 예제를 제공해 LLM의 성격을 다듬고
to work from, and also to prime it with information that might be useful later.
나중에 유용할 정보를 프라임으로 함으로써요
It's interesting that this feels a bit like training because it's learning from multiple examples,
훈련 같은 느낌이 드는 게 흥미롭네요 비트 코스트는 여러 예시를 통해
but of course, this isn't training in the data science sense.
배우지만 데이터 과학적 측면에서는 아니죠
The model has already been trained.
모델은 이미 훈련받았어요
The neural network training has happened.
신경망 훈련이 끝났어요
This is all at what we call an inference time at runtime.
런타임에서 추론 타임이라고 부르는 때죠
It's all just generating future tokens based on past.
과거에 기반해 미래 토큰을 생성하는 거죠
But the point is that if that past set of tokens includes a bunch of questions and answers, then when
하지만 중요한 것은, 과거의 토큰들이 질문과 답변을 담고 있다면 미래를 예측할 때,
it's predicting the future, it's more likely it's more likely to pick future tokens that are consistent
미래의 토큰을 선택할 가능성이 더 높다는 것입니다. 과거에 봤던 것과 일관되는
with what it's seen in the past.
것으로요.
And that's why this works so very well.
그래서 이 장면이 잘 된 거예요
So we're now going to build a chatbot.
챗봇을 만들 거예요
Our first chatbot.
첫 챗봇이에요
And it's going to look like this.
이렇게 될 거예요
It's going to have a sort of instant message style interface to it with questions from us, responses
일종의 인스턴스 메시지 스타일 인터페이스가 있을 겁니다 저희의
from the chatbot in this sort of interface, which, you know, that's that's reasonably sophisticated
질문과 챗봇의 응답이 있는 이런 종류의 인터페이스죠 꽤나 정교한 겁니다
and I'm telling you that we're going to be able to do it all in this one lesson, and it will give you
이 강의에서 전부 다 할 수 있다고 말씀드리는 거예요 미래에 같은 걸 할
tooling to be able to do the same thing in the future.
수 있는 도구를 줄 거예요
So without further ado, let's go over to JupyterLab.
그럼 바로 유피터랩으로 넘어가죠